# MANUEL F. CHAVEZ

## MECHATRONICS ENG.

### CONTACT

+49 152 21795849

ffferchavez@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ffferchavez

Dresdener Str. 14, 47533 Kleve, Germany

#### SKILLS

- Proactive
- · Fast learning and adaptability
- Precision
- Get Things Done mentality
- Critical thinking and problem solving
- · Oral and written communication skills
- Team work
- · Impeccable self-management
- · Initiative and decision-making

# EDUCATION

 ${\bf B.Sc.\ Mechatronics\ Systems\ Eng.}$ 

## **Rhein-Waal Hochschule**

2019-2023

Zertifikat in Deutsch für Zuwanderer

# Mehrgenerationenhaus Frankenthal

2018-2019

Ingenieria en Mecatronica

## Universidad de Sonora

2011-2017

#### Mecatronica

Centro de Bachillerato Tecnologico Industrial y de Servicios No. 11 2008-2011

#### LANGUAGES



#### PROFILE

My name is Manuel Fernando, I am 29 years old and I live in Germany.

I specialize in the area of Mechatronics Systems, with major interest in CAD-Design, Software/Hardware Development and Electronics.

Years of experience in areas such as Materials Testing, Manufacturing, Automotive and Design in different companies, countries and cultures have expanded my beliefs and ideas, giving me different perspectives on things

I try daily to keep up with Top problem-solving abilities and proactivity.

Effective communication and teamwork skills.

Always with high level of attention to detail, I try every day to improve myself as professional. I also believe in the capacity to clearly explain technical concepts to non technical audiences. My hobbies are 3D printing, laser engraving and cutting, self-learning and books, and musical instruments.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Systems Manufacturing**

AMETEK, inc. - Materials Division Spectro Analitycal Instruments GmBH 03/2022 - Actual

Construction of elemental analysers with optical emission spectroscopy and X-ray fluorescence spectrometry.

The structure of the SPECTROGREEN ICP-OES in three model variants:

- Dual Side On Interface (DSOI).
- Twin Interface (TI).
- Side On Plasma Viewing (SOP)

## **Materials Testing Technology**

WTBrinkmann GmbH

11/2021 - Actual

Main functions:

carry out the test of welding materials with the following methods:

- Visuelle Inspektion (VT) / Visual inspection (VT)
- Durchstrahlungsprüfung (RT) / Radiographic Testing (RT)
- Magnetpulverprüfung (MT) / Magnetic Particle Testing (MT)
- Mobile Härteprüfung (HT) / Mobile Hardness Testing (HT)
- Ultraschallprüfung (UT) / Ultrasonic testing (UT)
- Eindringprüfung (PT) / Penetrant Testing (PT)

Then, evaluation of results and report of failures.

### **Automotive Mechatronics**

LDJ KFZ Service BMW MINI

Main functions:

08/2021 - 01/2022

Computer problem analysis.

repair of electrical and mechanical systems such as electronic modules and wiring, as well as mechanical repairs on engine, transmission, brakes and suspension. Including special works such as restoration of classic car parts or modifications such as body kits.

# MANUEL F. CHAVEZ

## MECHATRONICS ENG.

#### CERTIFICATES

- Mechatronics Diploma
- · Mechatronics Certificate
- Altium Designer Education -Certificates
- Integrationskurs Leben in Deutschland
- TELC B1/B2 Deutsch-Test für Zuwanderer
- Toefl IBT

#### EXPERTISE

- CAD-DESIGN
- VISUAL STUDIO
- PCB LAYOUT-DESIGN
- MICROCONTROLLERS
- 3D PRINTING MACHINES
- DIODE LASERS
- ELECTRONICS

# REFERENCES

MEng. Ricardo Amaya Martinez		
	ŭ	+52 1(662) 936 6242
	$\boxtimes$	ricardo.amaya@unison.mx

#### Maria Tsonidou

+49 173 7057515

mariatso.1993@gmail.com

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Aluminum Elements Production**

Aluxe GmbH

08/2020 - 09/2021

Main functions:

Construction of windows and sliding doors as well as window walls made of aluminium.

Working with graduated cutting tables

Control of the CNC machine Emmegi Precision TS2.

Tasks with milling machine.

Tasks with many different tools such as flex, drill, measuring tools, etc.

good teamwork and proactive personality.

Precision and quality in every task I had to accomplish.

Production reports in Excel.

# **Program Manager (Geology Department)**

Universidad de Sonora

09/2014 - 12/2018

Main functions:

Organization of study plan for students, teachers, coordinators and workers. Operation of internal programs in collaboration with the IT department.

#### **Electronic Technician**

Ford Motor Company

2012 - 2014

Main functions:

Analysis of electronic systems through electrical diagrams and computer, repair of electrical and electronic modules, change of parts, programming of keys and computer module, repair of harnesses and connectors, report of failures and repairs,

preroll test

# Auto/Motorcycle/Diesel Mechanic Assistant (Weekends)

Mechanic Workshop Chavez

2006-2016

 $\label{thm:mechanic work such as oil change, wheels change/repairs, etc.$